Emil Reji

Profile

I'm a full stack Software Engineer based in the Greater New York City Area. I am a co-creator of Stagehand Framework, a drop-in service for automatically deploying and managing review apps for front end applications. I have experience in a variety of technologies including, but not limited to the Ruby and JavaScript Ecosystems. I also have extensive experience working with cloud environments such as AWS, Docker, Github Actions, etc.

Professional Experience

Co-Creator, Software Engineer, Stagehand-Framework

08/2020 - present

https://stagehand-framework.github.io/ □

- Co-Created Stagehand, an open-source drop-in solution that automates review apps for frontend applications
- Designed and implemented the AWS infrastructure using a Cloudfront CDN, IAM Permissions, Cloudformation Automation, Lambda@Edge Functions, S3 Buckets, and EC2 Instances
- Used Github Actions to automate review app creation and tear down in response to Github events
- Used service workers and other client side code to implement a dashboard for the review app users while simultaneously solving our complex routing issues
- Created an npm package to provide a simple CLI that pulls together Stagehand's architecture
- Co-authored documentation for the npm package
- Co-authored Stagehand's case study https://stagehand-framework.github.io/ ☑
- Collaborated daily with the rest of Stagehand's remote team

Software Engineer, Self-Employed

11/2018 - 08/2020

- Built a variety of projects including but not limited to the ones listed below
- A ticket tracker app using Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL, and RSpec
- A trello clone app using Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL, React, and Redux
- An airline routes app using React

Software Engineer, Senior Associate, Infosys

09/2018 - 08/2020

- Worked as a tester and a developer using Java, Spring, Oracle, SQL, Python, Angular, Jenkins, Agile, etc.
- Was selected as part of Infosys's #FlyingHigh Associate Success Stories
- Worked remotely across multiple time zones world wide

Skills

Back End Node.js, Express, Ruby, Ruby on Rails, Sinatra, SQL, MongoDB, REST API's, GraphQL, Webhooks, Java

Front End

JavaScript (ES6), React, Redux, HTML/CSS, Gatsby, Next.js, jQuery

Cloud

AWS, Digital Ocean, Heroku, Vercel

Tooling/Other

Git/Github, Docker, Jenkins, Agile Development

Education

Bachelors of Science in IT, Minor in Computer Science,

2014 - 2018

Montclair State University

GPA of 3.725 on a 4.0 scale

Information Security Certificate,

2016 - 2017

County College of Morris